I found myself lost and alone on this journey
Though my heart wandered far and wide, I could move not an inch
But now I can depart for any distant land
Now that we've met on this road
Even the unfamiliar songs of travelers
Can spark nostalgia in me when I'm with you
If the world we dreamed of exists somewhere,
Then let's go search for it beyond the wind
Through chilling dawns,
Through arid noons,
Through shivering nights,
Let's go see what lies at the end
What's the matter?
There are tremors in the air.
We're near the market.
Isn't that the cause?
No, I can feel it.
Water?
The sound of splashing water.
Where?
Ahead of us.
This won't do. We have to turn back!
Is this the only path?
There weren't any forks in the direction we were going.
Even I lack the confidence to find my way around here.
What's wrong?
They'll catch us even if we run.
They've set dogs after us.
What?
So foolish-sounding, that baying.
You should cover your ears.
What the hell was that?
I want some apples...
I'll buy you as many as you'd like later.
Wolf and a Silent Farewell
How on earth did they find us?
They probably ran into us by chance while they were looking underground.
If they knew exactly where we were, they would have cornered us by now.
Milone Trading has betrayed you!
There's no point in running!
Sounds like we've been sold out.
We must have come at a high price.
After all, they can run Milone's branch office into the ground if they have you.
I see. That would call for a high price indeed.
Sounds like a garden variety bluff to me.
Once we turn this corner...
I found them!
There they are!
Don't let them get away!
Do you know which—
It's this way. We're fine!
Turn left here!
No!
Sorry, but we're in a hurry.
Lawrence!
Lord Almighty, please forgive my sins.
Even if God forgives you, it seems that you angered Lady Luck somewhere along the way.
Damn it.
He got me.
Lawrence!
What a relief.
You weren't moving when I called to you.
I'm fine.
I was just a little tired.
Pull it together.
We're almost there.
Where?
Weren't you listening to me?
I can smell the warmth of the sun ahead.
Didn't I tell you there's a way to the surface nearby?
Yeah, that's right.
What's this?
You didn't even notice that?
No, of course I noticed. I'm fine.
We're almost there.
We'll be at the exit once we turn right at the end of the path.
Look!
It can't be...
An abandoned well, huh?
I'm sorry. I didn't think it'd end up like this.
There they are!
We found them!
Stay back.
No...
You can't—you're barely standing!
Don't you worry.
I'll be just fine.
That's a lie! I don't need my ears to know that's a lie!
I wondered, given the description we got.
But who would have thought it'd really be you,
Lawrence.
The man behind Medio Trading is Count Ehrendott.
A large wheat-producing land is capable of designating a silver currency of their choice for all their transactions.
The elimination of wheat tariffs would be a blessing not only for Medio Trading and the Count,
but for those in the village as well.
You personally know the merchants who buy wheat from the village.
The village chief has entrusted everything to you as well.
Wheat sales reach their peak right after the harvest, too.
Well, let's catch up later.
We don't have much time.
Don't be so cold.
We hardly got to see each other when I last visited.
Ah, but you met someone else, didn't you?
Hand her over to us.
We'll present her to the Church and put the old ways to rest forever.
If we do that, we'll be able to destroy Milone Trading.
When the tariffs are lifted, the profit from our wheat will skyrocket,
and those we sell it to will be rich indeed.
Lawrence, our village still remembers that you bought
wheat from us when we were suffering from heavy taxation.
It would be no trouble to give you purchasing priority now.
Lawrence...
Let's finalize this deal and open a store in this town together.
As a merchant, surely you can figure gain and loss.
You're right.
I've always wanted to realize that dream.
Lawrence!
However, an honest merchant abides by his contracts.
Fate works in strange ways.
A peculiar wolf I've picked up wants to return to the north.
I have a contract to accompany her there.
It goes against my principles to willingly breach a contract.
You...
I'm sorry our friendship was a short one.
A merchant is always saying goodbye.
You can kill the man.
Bring her in alive.
Let's see what you've got.
Holo!
My dagger!
Enough!
This might hurt a little...
Please bear with it.
She's sucking his blood!
Don't be afraid! She's only a possessed girl.
Don't...
Don't look at me.
You gods are always like that...
Always...
Always making life unfair...
Holo, don't!
Wait!
Holo!
H...
How much do you think those clothes you ruined cost me?
I don't care if you're a god or not! You're going to pay for it in full!
The fifty coins left over from what you earned aren't even a fraction of what you owe!
How many years do you think it took me to save that kind of money?
I'm going to follow you.
I'll follow you to the northlands if I have to!
Holo!
You're awake, are you?
How's your wound doing?
It feels better, thank you.
I must apologize for putting you through such danger through our ineptitude.
Don't. My companion was the cause of this, after all.
It was fortunate that the melee happened underground.
If someone else saw her in that form, our headquarters and branch stores would be ablaze by now.
You saw her true form?
Yes. I received a report from an agent
who said that a gigantic wolf would not hand you over until I came personally.
What happened to Holo?
She left without saying a word after we brought you here.
I see.
How did the negotiations go?
We were able to obtain the rights that I expected Medio Trading would want most.
That's wonderful.
We were able to collect 307,112 silver coins.
The king plans to reissue a severely depreciated version of the silver coins,
and we are to be paid with the cash value of 350,000 pieces at the time of delivery.
Three hundred and fifty thousand!
Our contract was to pay you five percent of our profit.
Do you have any objections?
No, that's correct.
Please confirm it for yourself.
This is...
One hundred and twenty silver coins. That is five percent of our profit.
It only amounted... to this?
Transportation costs for the coins
we collected, taxes levied on those very coins,
and the processing fee for the contract were all taken into consideration.
They imposed a rather excessive processing fee.
The King's advisors probably put him up to it.
They had to give up those privileges, but they minimized their losses on the currency exchange.
It was beyond what we could foresee.
It's just unfortunate.
When it comes to business, expect the unexpected.
However...
Unexpected situations can work out happily as well.
This is...
Medio Trading was desperate for those special privileges.
And they were collecting silver coins that were guaranteed to depreciate.
Keeping them would be little different from holding a debt.
They probably wanted to turn any kind of profit at this point in time.
We didn't have to think twice about their offer.
One thousand for me, though?
Really, it's a trifle.
Will silver coins be fine?
If you'd prefer payment in commodities, we can have that arranged.
Pepper.
Do you have pepper?
It's light, compact, and as winter falls, its price will rise as meat becomes more popular.
Is something wrong?
Excuse me. It just reminded me
of a particular play I recently read.
Play?
Indeed.
A religious play created by the Church to advocate restraint among traders.
Once upon a time, the devil appeared in front of a wealthy merchant.
"Bring forth the tastiest human around or I shall devour you!"
The merchant feared for his life.
He offered a young maid and a fat serf, but the devil shook his head.
After searching across the town for a luscious human being,
he finally came across a boy who smelled of honey and milk.
But when the merchant offered the boy to the devil, the boy said,
"The tastiest human is right in front of you."
What the devil saw was a man who ate spices daily,
and whose fattened soul was perfectly seasoned.
I was just imagining a fattened Mr. Lawrence
being devoured by the devil.
I wouldn't mind having a body seasoned with spices.
I'm looking forward to it.
I'd like to have many fruitful dealings in the future, Mr. Lawrence.
Thank you very much.
I must return to my work.
Mr. Lawrence, an invoice addressed to you has just arrived.
I don't recall buying any of this.
Which way is the loading dock?
Go straight ahead, make a right, and...
Thanks!
Out of the way!
Sorry!
A robe, a silk sash, traveling shoes, a tortoiseshell comb,
and last but not least,
tons of apples.
That'll be a total of a hundred and forty silver coins.
Holo!
Sorry, let me through.
I wouldn't want you to come all the way to the northern woods just to collect on a debt.
Geez.
I'll return home only after I've repaid you.
That goes without saying.
Some spice and a wolf, huh?
Next Episode: "Wolf and the Tail of Happiness."